ONUR OVALI

Summary

Product manager based in Istanbul w/ 10 years of product development experience (5 years - software development & 5 years - product management), all in online products. CS graduate with an MBA. Expertise in focusing on true problems, defining metrics for improvement, and creating digital products/services that get the jobs done w/ lean & agile practices. Interested in building amazing international products that solve people's problems.

Employment

Head of Product Management

Kariyer.net

May 2019 - Present

Managed the product team of 8 PMs, responsible for Kariyer.net Job Board (B2C), Kariyer.net Applicant Tracking System (B2B) and İşin Olsun (blue collar job board & ATS) and micro products like iskolig.com & HRVenue.com.

- Due to little employer information on the job ads, re-designed company profiles on the job board (with the CMS on the ATS). The company profiles' **traffic tripled**.
- Designed a **personalized** Profile page, offering relevant content for logged in candidates. Resulted in 40% increase on the ratio of updating resume and 30% increase on the users who view a job ad page after login.
- Changed the **UX** of the *posting a job ad* process and **increased job ad details by 30%**; improving the candidate experience, allowed more detailed candidate fit scores thus improving the employer experience.
- Designed **Smart Job Ad** product offering best-fitting candidates on the platform, helping employers on *finding* the right talent easily. Adopted fast by the market, **increased the base revenue / job ad**.
- Added KVKK (GDPR) Module, Assessment Tests, Video Interviews & Survey Module, OTP, Advanced Candidate Search Module and CMS for company profiles on ATS. Increased non-essential products' revenue by 40%.

Product & Marketing Manager

Turna.com

Dec 2017 - Apr 2019

Managed product analytics and marketing performance campaigns for Turna.com - one of the leading e-commerce platform for flight tickets in Turkey.

- Created **automated funnel reports** for each channel (apps & web), used for **conversion rate optimization**. Decreased payment errors by 15% and increased total **conversion rate by 30%**.
- Created automated ROI & P&L reports for campaigns, optimized budget allocations. Improved ROI by 90%.
- Created **customer lifetime value** (LTV) report, interviewed top 50 customers. With insights, discovered new segments. Designed new campaigns and **gained new customers with high LTV**.
- Defined behavioral segments and run email marketing campaigns. Achived better results (higher conversion rates and lower CPAs) than paid campaigns. Thus, designed an inbound marketing automation project which became an R&D project supported by government due to its improvement models with Machine Learning.

Technical Product Manager

Biletbank.com

Aug 2015 - Aug 2017

Led the microservices transformation project for B2B online travel agency (SaaS product).

- Software was in **monolithic** architecture. Started the microservices transformation project. Created the **architecture of all services' interfaces** and the **database designs**.
- Analyzed business requirements, created user stories, designed new data structures and processes.
- Defined the MVP, planned the project, created & prioritized tasks and managed the backlog.
- By implementing **branching** and **automatic deployment**; solved productivity problems of development team.
- Presented **Scrum & Agile** to the team, convinced using them and **increased efficiency**. Managed development & synch. of multiple teams and products with **Lean Startup** methodology; met deadlines and project targets.

Software Developer / Analyst

T. İş Bankası A.Ş.

Nov 2010 - Aug 2015

Full-stack developer for Isbank Internet Branch - one of the biggest private banks in Turkey.

- Developed web services for 2 factor authentication methods including OTP generators and iOS Touch ID.
- Performed **bug tracking** for internet branch, coordinating work of multiple teams with an SLA for open bugs.
- Supported IT Security team with Intrusion Detection Tests, after passing ISACA CISA June 2012 exam.

Education

MBA

Koç University, Istanbul

Sep 2015 - Dec 2017

- General MBA Program with a focus on innovation management, entrepreneurship & marketing.
- International attendance:

§ IE Business School, Madrid, Spain: Sales & Marketing (Erasmus Program)	Aug-Dec 2017
§ Hitotsubashi ICS, Tokyo, Japan: Innovation X Globalisation: Japan Style	Mar 2017
§ IE Business School, Madrid, Spain: High Tech Entrepreneurship (online course)	Jan-Mar 2017
§ Yale SOM, New Haven, USA: Behavioral Economis, Marketing & Finance	Oct 2016

BSc in Computer Engineering

METU, Ankara

Sep 2005 - Jul 2010

• Bachelor's Degree on Computer Science Program with a focus on algorithms, OOP & Al.

Certifications

 Deeply Practical Project Management issued by Udemy. Credential ID: UC-LCHJ8SAA 	Sep 2018
 Advanced Google Analytics Certificate issued by GA Academy. Credential ID: 234472174 	Aug 2018
• ISACA CISA (Certified Information System Auditor). Exam passed, certification not received.	Jun 2012

Skills, Knowledge & Tools

Product Management

- Experience on product strategy, market analysis, growth, benchmarking, product analytics & user interviews.
- Worked on software development, project management and product management sides of **product development cycles** in different **agile teams** and companies, mostly using **Scrum**.
- Deeply experienced on writing user stories, creating flow diagrams with detailed case analysis; allowing simple & clear briefs for design (UX/UI professionals) & development teams.
- Prioritization, backlog & shareholder relations management is an everyday task.
- Hands-on experience on project mng. tools: Jira, Confluence, SmartSheet, Trello, Basecamp, Asana & others.

Analytics & Digital Marketing

- Advanced knowledge on analytics tools **Google Analytics**, **Datastudio**, **GTM**, **Firebase** & Kochava.
- Advanced on managing **performance campaigns**: segmentation, reporting & optimization.
- Hands on reporting experience on Google Ads, FB Business Mng & Criteo.
- Advanced knowledge on office programs (Excel, Powerpoint, etc.).

Computer Science

- Deep knowledge on SQL with professional experience on T-SQL & Microsoft SQL Server.
- Advanced knowledge on CS basics: Algorithms, Data Structures, Database & web services design.
- Professional coding experience on **Python** & **C#**, basic knowledge on Java, C++.
- Best practices of **RDBMS** & **NoSQL** (Couchbase, MongoDB) usage.
- Basic knowledge on cloud computing on AWS & cost optimization.

Languages

Native in Turkish, fluent in English, intermediate in Spanish & beginner in German.

written in LATEX